Application Letter

From

J.George Kennedy,

No.2, 2nd Cross Street.

New Colony, Irugur,

Coimbatore – 103.

To

The HR Department,

Dear Sir,

Sub: Application for the post of – Reg

I'm very happy introduce myself as **George Kennedy.J**, a **Diploma holder in Electrical and Electronics Engineering with "C" License having 25 + years of experience** in various Electrical engineering fields production all type pumps and Motors, R & D and I.S.I. Works like utility maintenance of A/C Machines & Chiller Plant and S.T.P plant maintenance and motor production, motor testing, HT / LT projects execution, Genset Maintenance and Instrumentation of textile and waste water treatment plants and project erection commission works. And all type CNC Machinery Electric MV Panel Maintenance

I'm currently working in Ranger Pupmps, Coimbatore as production Manager, I herewith enclosed my resume clearly informing all my professional and personal details for your kind perusal.

Hope My qualification and experience will matches with your expectation and I'm assuring you that I'll deliver the best of my knowledge and skills for the development of organization as well as myself.

Expecting your favorable reply at the earliest.

Thanking you.

Yours Truly,

Place:

Date:

(George Kennedy.J)

CURRICULUM VITAE

J.GEORGE KENNEDY No.2, 2nd Cross Street,

E- Mail address: <u>kennedytwic@gmail.com</u> New Colony, Irugur,

Mobile No: 75987 01003, 8838721677 Coimbatore – 641 103.

Experience Details:

1. ORGANIZATION : S.N. Industries (Ranger Pumps)

POSITION HELD: Production Manager, (Production & Maintenance)

Package: Production off all Type of Domestic and Agricultural Pumps

Responsibilities:

- 200 KVA EB & DG MV panel Maintenance
- 125 KVA DG Set & Capacitor panel Maintenance
- 2 Nos CNC M/c & 16 Nos Lathe and 5 Ton Hydralic press Maintenance
- All type Eclectic control panel testing & Erretion and communion
- Manage material & Man power
- Production off all type submersible pumps & motor
- New development of 2 Phase Motor and submersible pumps
- Maintain IS 9283, 8034, 14220 and 8472 Licenses.
- Given Trainee of all type of Employees and staffs work with safety norms and quality production.
- Arrange Dealers meeting to privacy of any Improvement of production.

Duration: 2nd June 2018 to still date

2. ORGANIZATION: Lotus Eye Hospital & Institute

POSITION HELD : Maintenance Manager

Package: Maintenance and Project Erection and Commission

Responsibilities:

- Split, Central and Duct A/c machine operation & Maintenance.
- 50 KLD Swedge Treatment plant operation and Maintenance.
- 36 Ton Chiller Machine operating and maintenance.
- Branches: RS Puram, Tirupur, Mettupalayam, Salem, Chochin 2 No's maintenance with Team.
- TNPCB following work and take consign orders.

- Fire and safety following work and take NOC Certificate.
- Workers of Corporate and Branches given fire wall Training works.

Duration: October 23rd 2016 to July 2017

3. ORGANIZATION: JJ PUMPS PVT. LTD.,

POSITION HELD: R & D Manager

Package: Various type of Agriculture using all type of pumps manufacturing and Factory Maintenance.

Responsibilities:

- Manpower & Material Management.
- Production of all type of Motor and Pumps in Agricultural and Industrial Bare Motors.
- New development of Swedge open well & Mono block pumps and take production.
- To development of V3 Submersible pumps and take production.
- To got IS 8472 New License for self priming pumps.
- Operate the machines & Control 130 employees to got energy efficient Production.
- Maintenance 10 Nos. CNC Machines and 60 Nos. Lathe machines and 40 Nos. all type of machineries.
- Maintained IS 8034, IS 14220, IS 9079 License and got New License also.
- Given trainee all type of employees and staffs to works safety norms and quality production.

Duration: 1st December 2014 to 22 Oct 2016

4. ORGANIZATION: GET WATER SOLUTION PVT LTD., (O & M)

POSITION HELD: ENGINEER TECHNICAL SERVICE / PLANT MANAGER

Package: Various Common Effluent treatment plants, Tirupur. (Angaripalayam, Karipudur (C.E.T.P))

Responsibilities:

- Revamping work done and start the C.E.T.P.
- Operate the plant 2 L.D. Method of all various equipments.(PT, Cloring, RO I & II, RO3, Nono, HRSCC)
- Erection and Commission of on line monitoring system (ACETP 55 Dying & KCETP 17 Units)
- Erection of Commission of 450 M³/ Day Multi effect evaporator system (Forced Circulation) Started and Operator 18th March 2014 (KCETP) Make: Chem Process.
- Brine distribution system of member unit of ACETP & KCETP Sites.

- Conveyance system maintained pipe line of RO Permit / Brine Distribution.
- Erection and Commission of 6 Ton Boiler and Equipment started and operator 18th
 March 2014 (KCETP)
- Erection and Commission of 300m³ / Day Nano filtration system operated from Dec 2014 at KCETP Tiruppur.
- Operator and Team Leaser as Control Team members (60 Nos) energy effective Quality norms.
- Monitoring of all type of motors and pumps efficient operation and maintenance
 (ABB, Crompton Greaves, Becon, Grand Force, Kishore, KSB, Miltanroy)

Duration: September 2011 to Nov 2014

5. ORGANIZATION: TAMILNADU WATER INVESTMENT COMPANY LTD (O & M)

Package: Various Common Effluent treatment plants, Tirupur. (Rayapuram, Mangalam, Pallavaram, Chennai)

POSITION HELD: SENIOR TECHNICIAN - ELECTRICAL

Responsibilities:

- Erection & Commissioning of all HV / MV Electrical Equipments as per P&ID and CEIG Norms
- Installation and maintenance of Online Instruments
- Performance Guarantee Test run
- Operation and Maintenance of the HT/LT Panels, Genset and Motors.
- Continuous Monitoring of the equipment performance
- Cost effective Energy Utilization

Duration: January 2008 - September 2011

6. ORGANIZATION: SRI DHANALAKSHMI FOUNDRY, COIMBATORE POSITION HELD: ENGINEER – PRODUCTION

Responsibilities:

- Production In charge of the company
- Production of all types of motors and pumps for Agriculture applications
- Factory and Foundry maintenance
- Coordination in getting ISI 14220 & IS-8034. Get 320 Model.

Duration: May 2004 - Jan 2008

7. ORGANIZATION: SRI VIDHYA ELECTRIC CORPORATION, COIMBATORE POSITION HELD: ENGINEER – PROJECTS (PART TIME)

Responsibilities:

- Erection of all types of HT/LT Panels and Genset.
- Transformer alteration work.
- Getting Safety certificate "FREE FROM FIRE" for erected plants.
- Bank modernization work with required Electrical Infrastructure.
- Erection of 11 KV / 22 KV Structure yards.

Duration: Nov 2001 – Dec 2005

8. ORGANIZATION: THE GENERAL ENGINEERING COMPANAY (GECO PUMPS), COIMBATORE.

POSITION HELD: PRODUCTION SUPERVISOR

Responsibilities:

- Production In charge of the company
- Production of all types of motors and pumps for Agriculture applications
- Factory and Foundry maintenance
- Coordination in getting ISI 14220 & IS-8034.

Duration: Oct 2000 to April 2004

9. ORGANIZATION: A.T.L TEXTILES LIMITED, TIRUPPUR.

POSITION HELD: ENGINEER - MAINTENANCE

Responsibilities:

- Overall maintenance planning including Preventive, Break down and shut down maintenance
- Erection and commissioning of WASTLA generator 1250 KVA (crude oil operation)
- Erection and commissioning of A.T.L TFO unit at Sathyamangalm
- Inspection, resolution of field problems.
- Supervising work to ensure quality and safety standards.

Duration: Jan 1999 to Oct 2000

10. NAME OF ORGANIZATION: TEXMO INDUSTRIES, COIMBATORE - 641029

POSITION HELD: TESTING SUPERVISOR

Responsibilities:

- ❖ All types of ISI motor testing
- ❖ Getting IS − 8034 approval for Submersible pumps
- Operation and maintenance power house and generator
- Work allotment thru Men and Material Management.

Duration: Nov 1994 to Dec 1998

Education Chronicle:

Education	Institute / university	Year of passing	%of Marks
Diploma in Electrical and Electronics Engg	Rama seetha Polytechnic Madurai	1994	66.7
Higher secondary	Government higher secondary school, Nagercoil	1991	78.1
SSLC	Carmel higher secondary school, Nagercoil	1989	62

Additional Qualification:

"C" License (C.No: 35013 DOI -26-04-07) Valid up to 25-04-2023

Personal Profile:

Date of Birth : 14.05.1974

Sex : Male

Marital Status : Married

Language Known : Tamil & English

Permanent Address : No.2, 2nd Cross Street,

Nationality : Indian

Current Salary : 5.8 lakhs per Annum Salary Expected : 7.5 lakhs per Annum

Declaration:

I, the undersigned hereby certify that to the best of my knowledge and belief, the data correctly describes my curriculum vitae, my experience and me.

Yours Sincerely,

(GEORGE KENNEDY.J)

